Guide to the Phi Beta Kappa, California Beta Chapter (Stanford University), Records SC0094
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Phi Beta Kappa, California Beta Chapter (Stanford University), records
1904-1970
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Phi Beta Kappa. California Beta Chapter (Stanford University)
SC0094
5.5 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
Official records of the Stanford Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa, 1930-1970. Contents consist primarily of lists of eligible candidates, official initiation programs, financial statements and some correspondence.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Administrative transfer, California Beta Chapter, Phi Beta Kappa, 1969. Administrative transfer, Academic Planning Office and President's Office, 1971. Series 3 transferred from SC1048 to SC0094, December 2016.
Information about Access
Series 1 Restricted: for more information contact the University Archivist.
Description of the Collection
Official records of the Stanford Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa, 1904-1970. Contents consist primarily of lists of eligible candidates, official initiation programs, financial statements, annual dinner meeting programs, annual reports to the national headquarters, executive council minutes, and correspondence.
Student activities.; Phi Beta Kappa. California Beta Chapter (Stanford University); Phi Beta Kappa. California Beta Chapter (Stanford University)
- Papers, Series 1
  - undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1930-1931 assorted files and lists (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and publications (Box 3)
- Papers, Series 2
  Arrangement
  Correspondence arranged by month and date
  - 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1918-1946 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Committee on methods of election, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings re Stanford chapter of Phi Beta Kappa, 1947-1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - List of students eligible for Phi Beta Kappa, 1946-1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - List of students eligible for Phi Beta Kappa, 1955-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Key Reporter, 1945-1949, 1951-1956, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual dinner meeting programs, 1946-1949, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Phi Beta Kappa annual open meeting, 1906-1909, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Phi Beta Kappa annual open meeting, 1912-1915, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The future of Phi Beta Kappa, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The founding of new chapters, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Phi Beta Kappa associates, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Phi Beta Kappa addresses, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Sample Phi Beta Kappa certificate of membership, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - A greeting to new members, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - A ritual of Phi Beta Kappa, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous: information for delegates; 21st annual Council of the United Chapters of Phi Beta Kappa; revision of laws and practices, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - List of deceased members of Stanford Phi Beta Kappa, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - for regular meeting of Stanford chapter of Phi Beta Kappa, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Initiation meeting (May 24); National nominating committee; Stanford Phi Beta Kappa annual meeting of the electorate (May 12), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Present addresses of old members, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chapter management and organization; deceased members; National Committee of Qualifications, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Information on Clark University, national procedure for determining eligibility; Report of the Committee on Admission Requirements for Phi Beta Kappa; Chapter Officers' Manual, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Stanford Phi Beta Kappa officers, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Transfer scholarship equivalents; procedure for Phi Beta Kappa initiates; press releases, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Press releases; meeting of western district Phi Beta Kappa (1955 August 31);Twenty-fourth Triennial Council of Phi Beta Kappa (1955 September 2) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Phi Beta Kappa faculty counts; press releases; procedures for initiates, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - National security policy seminar, schedules of topics and speakers; chapter secretaries; press releases, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Deceased members list; press releases, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Deceased members list; press releases; proposed changes in chapter by-laws, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Press releases, procedure for initiates, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Delegate information for the 26th Triennial Council of United Chapters of Phi Beta Kappa; biographical sketches of nominees for officers, senators, and nominating committee members; press releases, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Deceased members list; minutes of meeting of western district of Phi Beta Kappa; press releases, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Press releases; questionnaire; visiting scholar program, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Agenda, chapter secretaries conference, 1964 Triennial Council meeting; information for various colleges seeking PBK membership; delegates manual, 27th annual triennial council; press releases (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Bulletin: 1945 December; 1946 February; 1948 February; 1949 February; 1953 March; 1954 January; 1955 February; 1957 January; 1958 February; 1962 March 1945-1962 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Phi Beta Kappa constitution and by-laws (local and national), undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Stanford chapter data; annual reports to national headquarters, 1944-1964 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, Santa Clara Valley Association of, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Stanford Executive Council minutes, 1945-1949 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Phi Beta Kappa directory, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Papers, Series 3
  - Charter of Phi Beta Kappa, 1904 Sep 7; AM-00-290 (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2018-055
  - Phi Beta Kappa Handbook, 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - Fifty Years of Phi Beta Kappa at Stanford, 1891-1941 (Box 1)